504 Suparshwa tower Venkatesh park, Bhayandar Mumbai , India. (91) 7738503795 kotharinimit8@gmail.com

# NIMIT KOTHARI

## DEEP LEARNING ENGINEER

#### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

Nimit Kothari is a Senior Software Engineer/Sr Analyst with 1 year 6 months of professional experience in the software industry. He is currently working as a Lead Developer in TechnologyConsulting Group. He has worked and introduced Machine learning as Microservice (MLAS),Image Recognition services using Deep Learning for the products, Email Notification using Python,Predix,Java. He is a Regional head of largest Blockchain community of Developers, Enthusiasts, Experts in India.He is Spearheading the team on Quantum Resistant Ledger.He is a part of ital Industrial Lab where he has orchestrated the Healthcare: Crowdsourcing of Hospitals.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Intermediate - Python, Microservices, Flask, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Quantum Computing

Beginner - Artificial Intelligence, Bluemix, Amazon S3, Solidity, Docker, Cloud foundry

On-going research/courses - Blockchain, Quantum Resistant Ledger, Quantum AI.

#### MANAGERIAL SKILLS

**Advanced** – Leadership, Communication, Blog Writing Skills, Time Management, Event Management, Teamwork, Speaker.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai — Senior Analyst (Technical Team Lead cum Business Analyst)
SEPTEMBER 2016 - PRESENT

- Machine learning engineer for one of the top firms in US and other countries.
- Developed machine learning services, deep learning services and deployed on the cloud.
- Developed chatbot using IBM watson api using NLP.
- Awarded as the star performer of the month for developing intelligent solutions.
- Revamped the solutions like Field services and Healthcare with intelligent & predictive features.
- Working on Healthcare Blockchain POC.
- Worked as lead developer, headed and directed team of machine & deep learning.
- Presenter for Healthcare crowdsourcing of hospitals.
- Developed email & sms notification service in python.

## **Blockchain India Community** — *Regional Head (Non-Technical & Technical)*

#### **DECEMBER 2017 - PRESENT**

- Organising & Managing Meetups for largest community of Blockchain Developers, Enthusiasts, Experts in India
- Conducting workshops and Training for corporates & students on Blockchain.
- Leading Quantum Resistant Ledger Team.

#### Personal Milestone:

Started out to be a front end developer gradually learned backend and machine learning skills. Now contributing to the github community. Interacting with Data scientist and Blockchain experts. Organising meetups and managing community. Exposure to cutting edge technologies.

## PAST:-

#### **Placement Co-ordinator, VCET**

JULY 2014 - MAY 2016

Worked as placement and training coordinator at vidyavardhini college of engineering. Managed campus and off campus placement drives.

#### Personal Milestone:

What started out to be a college core committee, turned out to be an opportunity that helped me to develop my managerial skills.

## **EDUCATION**

## Vidyavardhini College Of Engineering, Vasai — Bachelor of Engineer (B.E), Mumbai University

August 2012 - May 2016

Successfully graduated scoring 7.3 CGPA.

## **FUTURE:-**

## **BLOG**

Working on a blog that will discuss technical trends like Machine Learning, Blockchain, AI, Quantum Computing and will go live on 30th May, 2018.

## **TRAININGS**

Completing Specialisation on Deep Learning from Coursera and Nanodegree on Front End from Udacity.

## ONGOING EVENTS

Organizing various meetups on Blockchain, Machine learning, AI in Mumbai involving various key experts in India.

## LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/nimit-kothari-72b01287

### **GITHUB**

https://github.com/Nimitkothari